mckinseyquarterly.com 2016-12-04

# Privacy policy | McKinsey & Company

McKinsey & Company (“McKinsey”, “us” or “we”) understands that your privacy is important to you. McKinsey is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personally-identifiable information, being any information that is capable of identifying you as an individual person, as you use this Site and the McKinsey Recruitment Portal. The scope of McKinsey’s commitment is described in this Privacy Policy. By submitting personally-identifiable information, you consent to McKinsey’s use of such personally-identifiable information as described herein. Please see our terms of use for more information about our on-line terms and policies in general. 

### What personally-identifiable information is collected?

McKinsey collects personally-identifiable information on certain areas of the Site when users register for or apply for jobs through the McKinsey Recruitment Portal, register for McKinsey.com newsletters and alerts, participate in our alumni activities,  sign up for conferences and events, and participate in user posting areas (such as bulletin boards, discussion forums and surveys). The personally-identifiable information collected may consist of information that you provide, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, and background information required to apply for a job. For recruiting purposes, the information collected may include other personally-identifiable information that you include on your resume and information that you submit as part of your application. In addition, McKinsey collects certain information that you do not visibly enter, such as your IP address, browsing pattern on the Site, click stream data, HTTP protocol elements, and the status of cookies placed on your computer by McKinsey. 

### How may McKinsey use my personally-identifiable information? 

McKinsey uses your personally-identifiable information to fulfill your requests for information, publish your letters to the editor or comments, process your requests to participate in conferences and events, evaluate any job applications, recruit personnel, distribute newsletters and alerts to you, personalize content that you view or receive, evaluate and improve our services, and for such other purposes as you may initiate or request. We may keep any of your personally-identifiable information on file and use it to contact you.

### How are cookies used? 

Cookies are small packets of information that are stored by your web browser. They are put on your web browser by the websites that you visit. These packets of information do not contain personal information about you but they do allow us to know if you visit the same website twice or if you visit related websites. 

The laws in many European Union countries require you to provide a form of consent before cookies are placed on your web browser unless the cookie is necessary for the website to work. 

There is no agreed standard for how companies comply with these laws. We do the following:

  * We only use cookies where they are necessary for our services or where you have provided your express or implied consent.
  * We respect your wishes, and you can inspect, delete, or block any cookies used by us by selecting the appropriate control in your web browser.
  * We support technologies that have been developed and are being developed for your web browser that allows you to be more selective about the cookies that your web browser will accept.

### What are “cookies” used for on this website?

McKinsey uses cookies to identify you and your interests and to track your use of the Site. We also use cookies to control access to certain content on our Site and to process any requests that you make with us.

To administer our website and for research purposes, McKinsey has also contracted with third parties to track and analyze anonymous usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and members. Such information is shared externally only on an anonymous, aggregated basis. These third parties use persistent cookies to help us to improve the visitor experience, manage our site content, and track visitor behavior.

McKinsey has also contracted with a third party to send e-mail to our registered members. To help measure and improve the effectiveness of our e-mail communications, the third party sets cookies. All data collected by this third party on behalf of McKinsey is used solely by or on behalf of McKinsey and is shared externally only on an anonymous, aggregated basis.

More specifically, McKinsey places the following cookies:

****Cookie****

| 

****Cookie Purpose****

| 

****Nature of the Cookies****

| 

****Cookie Type****

| 

****Approval Method****  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Google Analytics: tracks each user's amount of visits, and the time of the first, the previous, and the current visit

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Google Analytics: tracks how long you stay on a site - when a visit starts and approximately ends 

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Google Analytics: tracks where a visitor came from

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Omniture SiteCatalyst: various reports on user activity

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Device Identification

| 

Identify your device (e.g. computer, phone, tablet PC) so that content is delivered in the correct format

| 

First Party

| 

Session

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
Language Identification

| 

Identify your language preferences when navigating the website

| 

First Party

| 

Session

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
Server Identification

| 

Identify the Server which served the request

| 

First Party

| 

Session

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
Session Identification

| 

Identify the Session which is currently used for maintaining your log-in; even if they are logged in or not

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
User Identification

| 

Identify the site User and grant access to the user's account

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
Print Specification

| 

Identify what pages the user wants to print

| 

First Party

| 

Session

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Used in connection with embedded videos delivered by Vimeo LLC to track anonymous information about the videos played, including the number of visitors and where visitors originated

| 

Third Party

| 

Temporary

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Session Tracking

| 

Used in connection with embedded videos delivered by Vimeo LLC to track problems encountered with the video player and improve performance

| 

Third Party

| 

Session

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Web Analytics

| 

Used in connection with embedded videos delivered by Brightcove to track anonymous information about the videos played, including the number of visitors and where visitors originated

| 

Third Party

| 

Temporary

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Session Tracking

| 

Used in connection with embedded videos delivered by Brightcove to track problems encountered with the video player and improve performance

| 

Third Party

| 

Session

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Session Identification and Analytics

| 

Pages on our websites may use a widget from ShareThis which facilitates users in sharing articles, links, and other information across various social media networks. The cookie uset determines whether a cookie has been set and the stid cookie tracks statistics related to use of the ShareThis widget.

| 

Third Party

| 

Temporary

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Session identification

| 

Used in connection with identifying the user or organization using the Organizational Capacity Assessment Tool (OCAT) on McKinseyonSociety.com

| 

Third Party

| 

Session

| 

Strictly Necessary  
  
User Tracking

| 

Optimizely uniquely identify users and track their measurable actions based on different content

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
User Tracking

| 

Optimizely uniquely tracks users across domains related to measurable actions with the primary first party cookie

| 

Third Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
User Identification and Analysis

| 

Pages on our website may use a widget from Twitter which facilitates interaction with its services.  Twitter tracks users for authentication and security, user preferences, analytics and research, and to serve personalized content

| 

First Party

| 

Permanent

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Session Tracking

| 

Used in connection with embedded videos delivered by YouTube to track anonymous Session Tracking information about the videos played, including the number of visitors and where visitors originated

| 

Third Party

| 

Temporary

| 

Implied Consent  
  
Definitions:

  * “First Party” Cookie – A cookie placed by this website 
  * “Third Party” Cookie – A cookie placed by another domain (e.g. not this website) 
  * “Permanent” Cookie – The cookie information is permanently stored on your device 
  * “Temporary” Cookie – The cookie information is stored for a defined period on your device (e.g. six months)
  * “Session” Cookie – The cookie information is temporarily stored in your web browser’s memory 
  * Implied Consent – You are deemed to have given your consent by continuing to use this website after having had this privacy policy made available to you 
  * Explicit Consent – You specifically agree to the use of cookies after having had this privacy policy made available to you 
  * “Strictly Necessary” Cookies – These cookies are required so the website can function. No consent is required 

We don't seek to collect your personal information, and, where we do collect it, we strive to anonymize your personal information as soon as practicable.

### McKinsey Recruitment Portal / McKinsey Retention Program

To assist McKinsey with its staffing and recruitment, McKinsey has partnered with SalesForce.com to provide the McKinsey Recruitment Portal. If you provide information through the Recruitment Portal, your personally-identifiable information will be held on servers located in the US, managed by SalesForce.com. SalesForce.com has agreed to provide the same level of privacy and data protection that you enjoy when interacting with this Site and McKinsey generally.

Through the McKinsey Recruitment Portal, job candidates can apply for positions with McKinsey or sign up for the McKinsey Retention Program where you can be notified of any potential job openings or other similar opportunities that might be of interest to you.

McKinsey frequently visits recruiting websites and social networks such as LinkedIn. Where users of those websites have made their personally-identifiable information publically available, McKinsey sometimes collects this information for the McKinsey Retention Program. If you do not want McKinsey to retain your personally-identifiable information collected in this way, please opt-out of the McKinsey Retention Program when notified that your personally-identifiable information has been collected.

### Mobile Applications

In connection with applications that we make available for mobile devices, McKinsey may use third-party services to track and analyze nonpersonally identifiable user activity in order to fix errors, monitor usage, and improve the performance of the applications. In particular, UrbanAirship tracks whether a user opened an application in response to a specific push notification. Omniture tracks and reports on some of our mobile applications’ usage and browsing patterns, including information about the type of device used, articles accessed, and other events occurring within our apps. Crittercism tracks certain errors occurring within mobile applications. None of these third parties gathers information in a manner intended to identify any particular user personally.

In addition, our McKinsey Insights app offers a personalized list of recommendations (called “Recommended for you”) pointing out McKinsey content we think you'll find interesting. Recommendations are based solely on what you've viewed in the Insights app. A unique user identifier that is generated by the app  helps by personalizing your experience and tracking the articles you read. We do not share your viewing history or trends with other users or any third parties.

Our mobile applications may include integration with various social-networking sites, including Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn, and Twitter. If you enable and use these features within an application, the extent to which your activities and information are tracked is governed by the relevant user agreement you have in place with such a third party.

### The Alumni Center, Newsletters, and Alerts 

By registering with our Alumni Center or for recurring McKinsey newsletters or alerts, you agree to receive on occasion other correspondence from McKinsey related to the subscribed newsletters and other McKinsey news and information that you consented to receive during registration. This type of information is shared externally only in anonymous, aggregated form for generalized user analysis or to enable third party agents to send e-mails to you on our behalf. You will be contacted by e-mail or otherwise only by McKinsey or it agents. 

We ask for your e-mail address at registration. We will send e-mails to this address to confirm your registration, to provide newsletters or alerts and to contact you for any other reason. In addition, we may contact you regarding your account status. If you sign up to receive any of our newsletters, alerts, or surveys, you may on occasion receive other correspondence from McKinsey. Your e-mail address will not be shared with any third party other than an agent who has agreed to send e-mails on our behalf. 

The Site also includes a feature that enables McKinsey to send links to its content through e-mail at our users' request. The e-mail address(es) that you supply in connection with this service will be used only to send the requested content. They will not be stored or reused for any purpose. 

### Is personally-identifiable information disclosed to third parties? 

McKinsey shall not intentionally disclose or transfer (and shall take reasonable steps to prevent the unauthorized or accidental disclosure of) your personally-identifiable information to third parties (i.e., persons or entities that are not affiliates of McKinsey) without your consent, whether for such third parties’ marketing purposes or otherwise, except as follows. McKinsey may provide access to your personally-identifiable information to third party vendors engaged by McKinsey to provide services related to the Site; provided that such vendors will first agree to maintain the strict confidentiality of such information and provide the same level of data security as provided by McKinsey. McKinsey may also be compelled to surrender personal user or customer information to legal authorities without express user consent if presented with a court subpoena or similar legal order, or as required or permitted by the laws, rules, and regulations of any applicable jurisdiction. Also, in the event of a violation of the Terms of Use of or any other terms on this Site, including but not limited to a violation of any restrictions on use of materials provided in or through this Site, McKinsey may disclose personal user information to affected parties and legal authorities in furtherance of potential or on-going legal proceedings. 

### Surveys

If you participate in a survey, all of our research results are reported as totals or in other aggregated form, and no information about you as an individual respondent is made public. 

### User forums

You should be aware that whenever you publicly disclose information online, that information could be collected and used by others. McKinsey is not responsible for any action or policies of any third parties who collect information that users publicly disclose in any such forums on the Site. 

### Link to third-party sites

McKinsey may provide links to third-party websites or information as a service to our users. If you use these links, you will leave this Site. Such links do not constitute or imply an endorsement, sponsorship, or recommendation by McKinsey of the third party, the third party website, or the information contained therein, and McKinsey shall not be responsible or liable for your use thereof. Such use shall be subject to the terms of use and privacy policies applicable to those sites. 

### How can I access, change, and/or delete information?

You may access, correct, update, and/or delete any personally-identifiable information that you submit to the Site. You may also unsubscribe from mailing lists or any registrations on the Site. To do so, please either follow instructions on the page of the Site on which you have provided such information, subscribed or registered or contact us at the address provide at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. 

### Security

McKinsey has implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personally-identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction. Only authorized McKinsey personnel and third party vendors are provided access to personally-identifiable information, and these employees and vendors are required to treat this information as confidential. Despite these precautions, McKinsey, however, cannot guarantee that unauthorized persons will not obtain access to your personally-identifiable information. 

### Transborder hosting and transfer of information

Personally-identifiable information collected on the Site may be transferred from time to time to McKinsey offices or personnel, or to third parties, located throughout the world, and the Site may be viewed and hosted by McKinsey or its vendors anywhere in the world, including countries that may not have the same data protection laws than what is found in your country of residence. By using the Site and registering such information on it, you voluntarily consent to such transborder transfer and hosting of such information. 

Without limiting the foregoing, in connection with client engagements involving specific services, McKinsey’s United States entities have certified to the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework with respect to certain personal information about its clients’ personnel located in the European Economic Area or Switzerland. McKinsey is aware that the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks may, in light of a 2015 ruling by the European Court of Justice, no longer constitute an adequate basis for the transfer of personal information to the United States. Nevertheless, McKinsey also believes that the Safe Harbor principles continue to represent important commitments for protecting the privacy and security of personal information, and McKinsey will continue to abide by these principles in the course of the specific services covered by its Safe Harbor certification, as well as with any other commitments made to its clients. For more information about McKinsey’s protection of such personal information and the process McKinsey follows, please refer to McKinsey’s privacy statement on certain international transfers. 

### Data Retention Policy

McKinsey stores personally-identifiable information for various purposes as notified to you in this policy. For each of these different purposes, McKinsey only retains the personally-identifiable information for so long as it is serving its notified purpose.

More specifically, McKinsey retains personally-identifiable information for:

****System****

| 

****Data Retention Purpose****

| 

****Retention Period****  
  
---|---|---  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Your contact details will be collected for the purpose of registering for the event.

| 

6 months after the event– Your contact details will be retained for the duration of the event and 6 months thereafter to assist with organizing the event.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

User forums and boards – To provide an environment for the open exchange of ideas.

| 

Indefinitely - Any personally-identifiable information made publicly available on user forums or boards will remain available indefinitely.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Contact details for submitted comments or contact us inquiries

| 

Indefinitely – Any personally-identifiable information will be retained for contacting purposes only.  
  
McKinsey Recruitment Portal

| 

Retain job candidate registration details for system access

| 

7 Years – Personally-identifiable information collected for login purposes will be retained for 7 years after the last login. At which time, McKinsey will ask the job candidate if they wish to keep their account active. If the answer is no or if there is no answer at all, the account will be deleted.  
  
McKinsey Recruitment Portal

| 

Check whether a job candidate has previously applied

| 

5 Years – McKinsey would like to know whether a job candidate has previously applied. A minimal amount of personally-identifiable information will be retained for this purpose, and it will be deleted after 5 years.  
  
McKinsey Retention Program

| 

Retain job candidate contact details and past application for individuals that have applied to McKinsey so that McKinsey might notify them of future opportunities

| 

7 Years – If a job candidate consents to McKinsey retaining their application and contact details, then McKinsey will continue to do so until either instructed to delete the information by the job candidate or 7 years of inactivity has passed. Once the 7 years has passed, McKinsey will ask the job candidate if they wish to keep their account active. If the answer is no or if there is no answer at all, the account will be deleted.  
  
McKinsey Retention Program

| 

Retain job candidate contact details for individuals whose personal data has been collected by a third party (e.g. recruiter, resume book, employment website...)

| 

7 Years – If a job candidate has given consent to the third party to collect their personally-identifiable information for employment purposes, then McKinsey will retain their contact details until either instructed to delete the information by the job candidate or 7 years of inactivity has passed. Once the 7 years has passed, McKinsey will ask the job candidate if they wish to keep their account active. If the answer is no or if there is no answer at all, the account will be deleted.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Retain contact details for distribution of McKinsey Newsletter and Alerts

| 

Indefinitely – Once registered, the user will continue to receive McKinsey Newsletters and alerts unless they ask to no longer receive delivery of email or the periodical.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Retain contact details for submitted customer service inquires

| 

Indefinitely – information submitted in connection with an inquiry is stored with the relevant submission.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Retain demographic information for members of the panelist program

| 

Indefinitely – for research and survey analysis.  
  
McKinsey.com

| 

Retain contact details for submitted comments

| 

Indefinitely – Any personally-identifiable information is either published with the article or stored with the article.  
  
McKinseyonSociety.com

| 

Retain contact details and data captured by the organization profile registration

| 

Indefinitely – stores the user information and organization for posterity.  
  
McKinsey Insights App

| 

Retain contact details for personalized experience 

| 

Indefinitely – Once registered, the user will be able to personalize knowledge topics and articles for all future sessions.  
  
McKinsey Insights App

| 

Retain contact details for submitted customer service inquiries

| 

Indefinitely – information submitted in connection with an inquiry is stored with the relevant submission.  
  
Alumni.McKinsey.com

| 

Retain registration details and other information submitted by users

| 

Indefinitely – information submitted in connection with our Alumni Center may be kept for use in accordance with our privacy policy  
  
### Children

McKinsey understands the importance of protecting children's privacy, especially in an on-line environment. The Site is not designed for or directed at children 13 years of age or younger, and McKinsey will not intentionally collect or maintain information about anyone under this age. 

### Consent; changes to privacy policy

By using the Site, you consent to the collection, use, and storage of your information by us in the manner described in this Privacy Policy and elsewhere on the Site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will alert you to any such changes by updating this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy was last updated on March 9, 2016.

### Contact our privacy department

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or if you require any assistance in navigating or reading the materials on this Site or any other McKinsey Sites, please contact us at:

McKinsey & Company  
Legal Department  
55 East 52nd Street  
New York, NY 10022  
212-446-7000
